<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yalchin Mammadli on Yalchin's Blog</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Yalchin Mammadli on Yalchin's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Yalchin Mammadli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 14:24:13 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Set Up GitHub Ssh Key</title><link>/blog/how-to-set-up-github-ssh-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:49:33 +0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-set-up-github-ssh-key/</guid><description>Github SSH Key set up
This tutorial will help you to be able to set up SSH key connection to your github account on a Linux machine. You can also continue to read this tutorial if you want to set up Deploy Keys.
For now let&amp;rsquo;s just assume that you&amp;rsquo;ve successfully set up SSH key, after that you need to make sure that you don&amp;rsquo;t access your repo with HTTPS, but with ssh, so if you previously cloned your repo wirh https set it to ssh as below:</description></item><item><title>How to Set Up Mailgun in Django</title><link>/blog/how-to-set-up-mailgun-in-django/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:41:10 +0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-set-up-mailgun-in-django/</guid><description>In this tutorial, I will try to cover configuring a custom domain for sending emails in your application. The benefit of using mailgun is that it allows you to send (5,000) emails for free during the first three months (then you will pay $0.8 per 1,000 emails) and its setup procedure is so straightforward. You will only need to add your payment verification to be able to send emails without any restrictions.</description></item><item><title>How to Deploy NodeJs App</title><link>/blog/how-to-deploy-nodejs-app/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:33:34 +0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-to-deploy-nodejs-app/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we will be deploying a simple URL shortener API built-in express framework of NodeJs. It is pretty simple, uses MongoDB as its database, and you can find its source code: https://yalchin.ml/Cq93RQ.
As a VPS, I use a Linode ubuntu server, and I assume that you have at least some basic knowledge when it comes to Linux.
Install Node and NPM curl -sL https://deb.nodesource.com/setup_12.x | sudo -E bash - sudo apt install nodejs # verify that bash is installed node --version Clone your Repo git clone [link to your github repo] Install npm dependency packages cd yourproject npm install npm start (or whatever your start command) # stop app ctrl+C To be able to run our app in the background continuously, we will be using a package called PM2.</description></item><item><title>Vim Cheatsheet</title><link>/blog/vim-cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:21:07 +0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/vim-cheatsheet/</guid><description>No Command Meaning 1 :w Save 2 :q Quit 3 :q! Quit without saving 4 :wq Quit with saving 5 k Navigates up 6 j Navigates down 7 h Navigates left 8 l Navigates right 9 i Enter insert mode 10 esc or ctrl +[ Enter normal mode 11 gg Navigates to the top 12 G Navigates to bottom 13 H High: takes you to the top of your code 14 M Middle: takes you to the middle of your code 15 L Low: takes you to the bottom of your code 16 nG Navigates to n-th line (example - 3G navigates to 3rd line) 17 { Navigates one code block up 18 } Navigates one code block down 19 nk N lines up 20 nj N lines down 21 nh N lines left 22 nl n lines right 23 u Undo 24 ctrl + r Redo 25 .</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/personal/contact/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 02:30:25 +0400</pubDate><guid>/personal/contact/</guid><description>Phone := +994 70 501 9780 Email := yalchinmammadli@yalchin.info Telegram := @mrRootLog</description></item></channel></rss>