<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yalchin Mammadli on Yalchin's Blog</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Yalchin Mammadli on Yalchin's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Yalchin Mammadli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 14:24:13 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First Personal Blog</title><link>/posts/first_personal_blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 22:31:31 +0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/first_personal_blog/</guid><description>So far I was trying to keep this website&amp;rsquo;s content identical to yalchin.info/blog which is my main website where I mainly write mixed tech blogs to solve some problems. I usually write those blogs not because I&amp;rsquo;m expert at them, but I write them, first, as a reference and second, as contribution to the growing programming society. Anyway, I was planning to write this post about my switch from Android (have been using it since I got my first phone) to IOS, but then I thought I might include some personal details as well.</description></item><item><title>Accent and Case Insensitive Search and Minimum Distance Calculator in Pymongo</title><link>/posts/mongo_db_autocomplete/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 14:22:27 +0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/mongo_db_autocomplete/</guid><description>Ellaborate case Before starting with set up and everything, I would love to confess that I find Mongodb and Python combination as pain in the ass. Recently I have got an job offer as Python/Flask developer in one of the local companies in my country. They are using Mongodb as their production database. They requested a little bit of task to accomplish before we move on to HR interview. So the task was about coding autocomplete search logic and also finding the closest location to our current location from the database.</description></item><item><title>Docker Compose for Elastic Search and Kibana</title><link>/posts/docker-compose-for-elastic-search-and-kibana/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 14:36:58 +0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/docker-compose-for-elastic-search-and-kibana/</guid><description>Command: docker-compose -f docker-compose.yml up -d Content of docker-compose.yml: version: &amp;#39;3.7&amp;#39; services: elasticsearch: image: docker.elastic.co/elasticsearch/elasticsearch:7.4.0 container_name: elasticsearch restart: always environment: - xpack.security.enabled=false - discovery.type=single-node ulimits: memlock: soft: -1 hard: -1 nofile: soft: 65536 hard: 65536 cap_add: - IPC_LOCK volumes: - elasticsearch-data-volume:/usr/share/elasticsearch/data ports: - 9200:9200 kibana: container_name: kibana image: docker.elastic.co/kibana/kibana:7.4.0 restart: always environment: - ELASTICSEARCH_HOSTS=http://elasticsearch:9200 ports: - 5601:5601 depends_on: - elasticsearch volumes: elasticsearch-data-volume: driver: local</description></item><item><title>How to Securely Connect to Virtual Private Server</title><link>/posts/how-to-securely-connect-to-virtual-private-server/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 14:26:43 +0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-securely-connect-to-virtual-private-server/</guid><description>For your information, this tutorial is not written by me absolutely, I&amp;rsquo;ve used ssh connection part of this tutorial and added some comments to make individual tutorial on &amp;ldquo;how to create your own vpn&amp;rdquo; and also covers the things that we can implement to make our vps the way more secure.
Generating SSH keys
Using a cleartext password to log in to your server is never a good idea since the password is not encrypted in transit and can be exposed on a hostile network.</description></item><item><title>How to Set Up GitHub Ssh Key</title><link>/posts/how-to-set-up-github-ssh-key/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:49:33 +0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-set-up-github-ssh-key/</guid><description>Github SSH Key set up
This tutorial will help you to be able to set up SSH key connection to your github account on a Linux machine. You can also continue to read this tutorial if you want to set up Deploy Keys.
For now let&amp;rsquo;s just assume that you&amp;rsquo;ve successfully set up SSH key, after that you need to make sure that you don&amp;rsquo;t access your repo with HTTPS, but with ssh, so if you previously cloned your repo wirh https set it to ssh as below:</description></item><item><title>How to Set Up Mailgun in Django</title><link>/posts/how-to-set-up-mailgun-in-django/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:41:10 +0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-set-up-mailgun-in-django/</guid><description>In this tutorial, I will try to cover configuring a custom domain for sending emails in your application. The benefit of using mailgun is that it allows you to send (5,000) emails for free during the first three months (then you will pay $0.8 per 1,000 emails) and its setup procedure is so straightforward. You will only need to add your payment verification to be able to send emails without any restrictions.</description></item><item><title>How to Deploy NodeJs App</title><link>/posts/how-to-deploy-nodejs-app/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 20:33:34 +0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-deploy-nodejs-app/</guid><description>In this tutorial, we will be deploying a simple URL shortener API built-in express framework of NodeJs. It is pretty simple, uses MongoDB as its database, and you can find its source code: https://yalchin.ml/Cq93RQ.
As a VPS, I use a Linode ubuntu server, and I assume that you have at least some basic knowledge when it comes to Linux.
Install Node and NPM curl -sL https://deb.nodesource.com/setup_12.x | sudo -E bash - sudo apt install nodejs # verify that bash is installed node --version Clone your Repo git clone [link to your github repo] Install npm dependency packages cd yourproject npm install npm start (or whatever your start command) # stop app ctrl+C To be able to run our app in the background continuously, we will be using a package called PM2.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/personal/contact/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 02:30:25 +0400</pubDate><guid>/personal/contact/</guid><description>Phone := +994 70 501 9780 Email := yalchinmammadli@yalchin.info Telegram := @mrRootLog</description></item></channel></rss>